So in my hand is a fiber based print and when you look at this print and you see it, you're automatically like well, what's going on with it?
It looks like it's ruined or damaged or something.
Fiber based prints will curl up like this, exactly like this and this is perfectly normal.
So what you want to do when you have a print like this is a couple of different things.
One: you could use a press, like I have right beside me which we're going to use in a few minutes, or you could actually flatten this print using, I've seen people use heavy encyclopedias, books, I've seen people also make a little contraption where they'll take wood and felt and just screw it down with some bolts, two pieces of wood.
I like using a press.
These presses are fairly expensive, they can cost a couple hundred dollars but they're a vital part of a darkroom.
Sometimes if you can find other friends who have a press, press is pretty important.
The other thing, before you press your print you want to make sure that this print is totally dry.
Now a fiber based print can take up to twenty four hours to dry depending on the humidity of your darkroom so don't ever try to put a wet print in a press.